# **ISAAC EMMANUEL**

#### **Full Stack Developer & Security Researcher**

Abeokuta / Nigeria ei@nsisong.com msisong.com

鼻 github.com/1cbyc 🖺 twitter.com/1cbyc 💼 linkedin.com/in/isaacnsisong

# **Professional Summary**

I'm a **full stack developer** with up to eleven years freelance experience in web development and seven years' experience building smart contracts. I started building websites in 2014 with WordPress, then went on to start building with PHP which has, in fact, become my gateway to every other skill I learnt over time. I got into blockchain in 2017, and once I got a hang of the space, I learnt to write solidity and typescript. Ever since, I have been involved in the development of more than 100 websites (either as the sole developer, or a member of the development team) and built a little over 17 live smart contracts. Additionally, I have about eight years of experience in offensive security, successfully delivering 126+ freelance projects spanning smart contracts, websites, bots, automation and safety-critical software. I also have serious interest in AI/ML, and quantitative development with a proven track record of leading a technical team and working with other developers.

### **Technical Skills**

Programming Languages: TypeScript, C, Python, PHP, Elixir, Rust

Frontend: React, Vue.js, HTML5, CSS3, Tailwind CSS

Backend: Node.js, Express, Laravel, Python Flask/Django

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis

Cloud & DevOps: AWS, Docker, CI/CD, Git, Google Cloud

Blockchain: Ethereum, Solidity, Nethereum, Smart Contracts, IPFS

Security: Penetration Testing, Bug Bounty Programs, Cybersecurity Assessment

**Machine Learning:** TensorFlow, PyTorch, Image Classification, AI/ML **Tools:** Visual Studio, IntelliJ, Git, Postman, Burp Suite, Wireshark

# **Work Experience**

# Founder & Full Stack Developer

#### Nsisong Labs | September 2016 - Present

- Overtime, I've managed up to 13 developers to build and maintain 90+ projects
- Developed full-stack applications using modern technologies and frameworks
- Conducted security assessments and provided technical consulting
- Implemented CI/CD pipelines and deployment strategies
- Led code reviews and maintained coding standards across client projects

# Junior Implentation Specialist (Campus - SSI)

#### ESET Internet Security (SSI) | May 2018 - September 2018

- I was actively involved in the Secure School Initiative project for tertiary institutions in Abeokuta
- I implemented lightweight cybersecurity solutions and security awareness programs for FUNAAB ICT, and FCE.
- I also did security assessments and vulnerability audits of the IT and network infrastructure of the schools involved.

#### IT Administrator

#### RCCG | September 2012 - February 2018

- Managed IT infrastructure and network systems for the church along with the media and engineering unit.
- Being a member of the media unit, I was involved in the development and maintenance of the church website for some of the Apapa Family Zonal headquarters.
- Implemented security measures for data protection and access control for CRM
- Planned and implemented media projects for some newly opened Apapa family parishes alongside our Regional Media director and was involved in some of the multimedia content production.

# Some personal projects I enjoyed working on:

# Web Applications

- NotePad Web Wanted to make an online note for myself. See GitHub
- 1cbyc Web Scraper Web scraping utility for data extraction with web ui. See GitHub.

#### API & Backend

- API-Auth Ready to use API authentication system for secure user and service access. See GitHub.
- **NextJS Blog API** Ready to use RESTful API backend for a Next.js blog platform. See GitHub.

#### Blockchain & Web3

- **EVM Auto Transfer Bot** Automated transfer bot for EVM-compatible blockchains. See GitHub.
- Web3 Secure Audit Vulnerability assessment and auditing tool for smart contracts. See GitHub

# Machine Learning & Al

- **Pneumonia Image Identifier** Developed image classification model for disease detection from X-rays using TensorFlow. See GitHub.
- **Neural Network Go** Neural network implementation in Go lang for educational and experimental purposes. See GitHub.

# Compilers & Interpreter

- Expression Evaluator Mathematical expression parser and evaluator I wrote in Common Lisp. See GitHub
- **BF Interpreter** Brainfuck language Interpreter I wrote because it looked like Lisp. Check GitHub.
- Rust Compiler Experimental compiler project I wrote in C for 8 months. See GitHub

#### **Utilities & Tools**

- **Network Analyzer** Custom tool for capturing and analyzing network packets and network traffic. See GitHub.
- BMI Calculator Fast Calculation Tool for lazy medics. See GitHub.
- File Encryptor Fully custom file encryption tool I wrote in C. See GitHub.
- Deriv mt5 Bot Faster trade management for Deriv/Synthetic traders. See GitHub

### **Developer Tools**

- Graph Drawing Method C++ implementation of graph visualization algorithms.
  See GitHub
- **HTTP Load Balancer (for Servers)** Full grade HTTP load balancer I wrote in Rust for high performance. Check GitHub

### **Security Tools**

- Offensive Security Payloads Collection of penetration testing tools and techniques. See GitHub.
- Encrypted P2P Messaging Fully custom no packet messaging protocol for privacy. See GitHub
- **CLI Domain Verifier** Tool for verifying domain ownership and configuration. See GitHub
- **Bad Actors Database** Community-driven repository tracking cybersecurity threats in Africa. See GitHub.

# **Open Source Contributions**

- 80+ public repositories on GitHub with active development
- Created educational resources for cybersecurity learning and published 314 leetcode solutions at some point. See my Leetcode.
- Contributed to major projects like Nethereum and some Laravel ecosystem tools
- Maintained multiple indie developer tools and VS Code extensions too

### **Education & Certifications**

**Mathematics and Computer Science** *NOUN - 2022* 

**Pasture and Range Management** *FUNAAB - 2017* 

# **Professional Achievements**

- **120+ Freelance Projects** successfully delivered across web development, blockchain development, automation engineering, bot development, offensive security and safety critical engineering.
- 90+ Projects managed and maintained as lead developer at Nsisong Labs
- Active Security Researcher with expertise in penetration testing
- Blockchain Developer with hands-on smart contract experience
- Open Source Contributor with significant community impact

# **Current Side Quest**

Exploring my interest in **Quantitative Development** as I've been building expertise in algorithmic trading systems, financial modeling and analysis and risk management systems

# Languages

- English (Fluent)
- **Efik/Ibibio**(Native)
- Yoruba (Fluent)

# References

Available upon request. Portfolio and code samples available at github.com/1cbyc